PHILLIP MATES RESUME

Northeastern, CCIS

308 West Village H

360 Huntington Avenue

Boston, MA 02115

Email: mates@ccs.neu.edu

http://www.ccs.neu.edu/home/mates/

+1 801 518 3298

Citizenship: USA, Brazil

STATEMENT

I have spent the last 2 years as a PhD student conducting research in the area of Programming Languages. I built formal models to explore the correctness of compilers and equivalences between programs. My graduate explorations have given me a deep understanding of the invariants and limits of languages and I am excited to apply my expertise in a practical setting.

**EDUCATION** 

Northeastern University, Boston, MA
MS in Computer Science, December 2014

Advisor: Amal Ahmed

University of Utah, Salt Lake City, UT

BS with honors in Computer Science, December 2011

Programmino & Research

EXPERIENCE

PROGRAMMING Research Assistant, University of Utah, UT

Built a static analyzer capable of statically verifying permission usage of Android applications. The analyzer targeted Dalvik byte-code and

supported higher-order control flow.

Mentor: Matthew Might

Software Engineer, Space Monkey, UT

Developed device monitoring software in Node.js during a brief period

between my undergraduate and graduate studies.

Software Engineer Intern, Google Santa Monica, CA

Built a domain name classifier to enforce policy violations and developed

internal analytics scripts. Mentor: Joe Vanderwaart

**Visiting Research Student**, Institute for Theoretical Physics, ETH Zürich Worked with Computational Physicists to create useful data management tools. Surveyed the field of Randomness Extractors and explored possible

implementation designs for use in Monte Carlo simulations.

Mentor: Matthias Troyer

**Research Undergrad**, Scientific Computing and Imaging Institute, UT Lead developer of an online visualization repository which leveraged the VisTrails system to foster collaboration and enable scientists to easily present and share their visualizations. Developer for the VisTrails open-

source provenance and workflow management system.

Mentor: Claudio Silva

2012 - 2014

2008 - 2011

Summer 2012

Summer 2012

2011

2010

2009 - 2010

TRAINING PhD summer schools

Oregon Programming Languages Summer School

2012 ♦ Institut Henri Poincaré thematic trimester:

Semantics of proofs and certified mathematics

2014

A Provenance-Based Infrastructure to Support the Life Cycle of Executable ICCS 2011 Publications **Papers** 

D. Koop, E. Santos, P. Mates, H. Vo, P. Bonnet, B. Bauer, B. Surer, M. Troyer, D.

Williams, J. Tohline, J. Freire and C. Silva.

International Conference on Computational Science

CrowdLabs: Social Analysis and Visualization for the Sciences SSDBM 2011

P. Mates, E. Santos, J. Freire and C. Silva

International Conference on Scientific and Statistical Database Management

The ALPS project release 2.0:

Open source software for strongly correlated systems JSTAT 2011

B. Bauer et al. (ALPS collaboration).

Journal of Statistical Mechanics: Theory and Experiment

Towards Supporting Collaborative Data Analysis and Visualization in a Coastal Margin Observatory CSCW 2010

E. Santos, P. Mates, E. Anderson, B. Grimm, J. Freire and C. Silva Workshop on The Changing Dynamics of Scientific Collaboration

Talks **Kripke Logical Relation for Affine Functions:** 

> The Story of a Free Theorem in the Presence of Non-termination Sept. 2013

The 2nd ACM SIGPLAN Workshop on Higher-Order Programming with

Effects, Boston, MA

Posters **Analyzing Android Applications with Abstract Interpretation** ICFP 2012

Student Research Competition

TEACHING **Teaching assistant**, CS2500 *Introduction to Programming and Computing* 2012,2014

Introductory undergraduate CS course at Northeastern University EXPERIENCE

modeled off of "How to Design Programs".

TECHNICAL **Proficient:** Python

Familiar: Java, C, Haskell, Racket, Coq Skills

REFERENCES ♦ Amal Ahmed, amal@ccs.neu.edu Assistant Professor

College of Computer and Information Science at NEU

Matt Might, might@cs.utah.edu Associate Professor

School of Computing at U of U

♦ Claudio T. Silva, csilva@nyu.edu Professor

Computer Science and Engineering at NYU Poly